OBISESAN, Olamilekan Oluwatunmise

+2348174538389 | olamilekan.obisesan1@gmail.com | Lagos, Nigeria

https://github.com/kelvin-oo | https://www.linkedin.com/in/olamilekan-obisesan-5287441b9

PROFILE SUMMARY:

Resourceful web developer and frontend developer/instructor, excellent communication and problem-solving skills. Brings enthusiasm and detailed understanding of programming languages to webpage planning, development and maintenance. Experienced in instructing and delivering sound lectures on frontend development. Sound technical knowledge of modern technologies such as HTML, CSS, JavaScript and frameworks such as React, SASS/SCSS and Tailwind.

SKILLS:

•	HTML/CSS	•	Version Control/Git/GitHub	•	Responsive Design
•	JavaScript	•	Rest API	•	Figma
•	React JS	•	SASS / SCSS	•	Materialize
•	Next JS	•	Tailwind CSS		
PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE					

Frontend Developer - InstaSkool Tech

August 2022 to October 2022

- Worked with a team to build an online learning website.
- Worked as a Frontend Developer and was focused on giving the site the best possible UI by writing lines of CSS code.
- Communicated with UI/UX designers, product manager and backend developers to ensure a well implemented site.
- Worked on the responsiveness of the site to make sure the UI looked good on all devices.
- Fixed bugs and made sure the website was up and running.

Lead Frontend Developer Instructor - ThinkPeople LTD (Project T-max) November 2022 to February 2023

- Created a comprehensive eight-week curriculum to teach students the basics of frontend development.
- Led other instructors on how to best implement the curriculum and deliver sound lectures.
- Taught students frontend development with a step-by-step process, from HTML to CSS, to JavaScript and React.
- Assessed students weekly and gave them projects to gauge their progress.
- Recorded Tutorial videos for students after class learning.
- Examined and graded students at the end of the program.

Web Developer - AbrahamtheFirst Media

January 2023 to present

- Created design mockups.
- Planned website design and development, converting mockups into usable web presence.
- Currently building the website using React JS.
- Communicated with client on what they want and what they hope to achieve with the website.
- Communicating with client on a daily basis to show progress and also make desired changes.

Web developer - The Style House Nigeria

April 2023

- Designed and developed a fully responsive website using React, Tailwind, and plain CSS, following the provided UI/UX design.
- Implemented custom features and functionality to improve user experience and performance, resulting in faster load times and increased user engagement.
- Utilized best practices for code organization, including component-based architecture and reusable CSS classes, to ensure scalability and maintainability.
- Worked closely with the design team and project stakeholders to ensure the website met all requirements and exceeded expectations.
- Deployed the website to a live environment, conducting thorough testing to ensure functionality and compatibility across multiple devices and browsers.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science - University of Lagos, Nigeria.

PROJECTS

Kelvin's Gym

Built and deployed a modern React fitness exercises app using multiple APIs, With the functionality to choose exercise categories and specific muscle groups, browse more than one thousand exercises with practical examples, pagination, exercise details, pull related videos from YouTube, display similar exercises, and much more.

Music App

Built a music player app using react, styled with CSS, consumed an API for dynamically generating songs and implemented features such as library, skip, loop, etc.

Photon

Designed a web application using HTML, CSS and JavaScript, consumed Unsplash API for generating pictures.

Listenfy

Built and deployed an improved version of Spotify music app with React 18, Tailwind, Redux and RapidAPI, with a modern homepage, fully-fledged music player, search, lyrics, song exploration features, search, popular music around you, worldwide top charts, and much more.

BudgetIt

Created a budget and expenses calculator app using React and styled with react styled components.

Coolors

Created a color generation, color matcher and color picker app for web designers, this app helps randomly generate colors and stores it in user local storage.